Dawood Khalid

Introduction

An experienced Mobile Applications developer who has a track record of successfully creating apps that are both well-received and commercially viable. Skilled in working on a team and incorporating input into projects and has the ability to always look for ways to improve upon an already existing app for customers to keep downloading it and enjoying it. Meticulous eye for detail and tenacity to never quit on something until it is absolutely perfect.

Experience

Softech Systems, Lahore - Mobile Application Developer November 2019 - PRESENT

• IOS Development (swift, swiftUI):

Worked as a Senior iOS Developer on Enterprise level products. Collaborated directly with Western teams as an outsourced resource. Implemented the best design patterns and architecture, suitable for products of such scope. Also incorporated any new and advanced technologies to always improve and expand our product.

Coding pixel, Lahore - Mobile Application Developer

October 2017 - October 2019

• IOS Development (swift):

Worked on iOS based mobile apps for two years. Implemented many third party libraries including google api, firebase, AWS database integration, S3 storage integration, Alamofire and many more. ALso Implemented core libraries like coreimage, pdfkit, avkit, avfoundation etc.

• IONIC Development:

Worked on ionic based hybrid app development for 6 months. Have used angular, typescript and node package manager(npm).

Education

Punjab University College Of Information Technology, Lahore — BSIT Aug 2013 - Aug 2017

Skills

Swift, SwiftUI, iOS SDK, XCode, Architecture Patterns(MVVM, VIPER), GIT, Core Data, Objective C to Swift Conversion, One Signal, FCM, Google API's, Alamo Fire, Cocoa Pods, Fully Customize UI, Constraint Understating, Complex UI Handling, Memory Optimization, Custom Camera Implementation, Socket IO, Live Tracking, S3 Storage, Animation, AWS RDBMS API.

Projects

• Facelift Cloud(swift, swiftUI):

iPhone Application to automate the marketing and advertising, on all social platforms, of your businesses from one platform.

Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/facelift-cloud/id1257074048

• Spabalon(swift):

iPhone Application for professional stylists to further increase their business and to find new opportunities. They can book appointments and buy recommended products from the stylists themselves.

Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/spabalon/id1457965584

• Restorat(swift):

Resto-Rat is a mobile application that supports collectors and restoration.

Link: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/resto-rat/id1247642457?mt=8

• Duet(swift):

iPhone Application to meet new people with interests similar to yours, and interact with them.